Register of the Arthur T. Vanderbilt Political, Professional, and Judicial Papers, 1902 - 1957
Arthur T. Vanderbilt Political, Professional and Judicial Papers, 1902-1957
- Folders of Engagements (Correspondence, Addresses, Photos)
  - Invitations declined, 1956-1957 (Box 271)
  - Articles, Reviews (Box 272)
- Book Reviews and Financial
  - Book Reviews, 1950-1957 (Box 273)
  - Bank statements and cancelled checks, 1948-1952 (Box 274)
  - Paid bills, contributions (Box 275)
  - Clippings re ATV appointment to the Bench (Box 276)
- Books, Articles, Addresses
  - Articles, 1934-1938 (Box 277)
  - Articles, 1939-1944 (Box 278)
  - Articles, 1945-1949 (Box 279)
  - Articles, 1950-1951 (Box 280)
  - Articles, 1952-1957 (Box 281)
  - Articles, extra copies (Box 282)
  - Articles,extra copies (Box 283)
  - Articles, extra copies (Box 284)
  - Articles, extra copies (Box 285)
  - Articles, extra copies (Box 286)
  - Articles, extra copies (Box 287)
  - Articles, extra copies (Box 288)
  - Books by ATV (Box 289)
    - Studying Law (Box 72a, 289)
    - The Doctrine of Separation of Powers (Box 289)
    - Judges and Jurors (Box 72a, 289)
    - The Improvement of the Administration of Justice (Box 289)
    - The Challenge of Law Reform (Box 289)
    - Men and Measures in the Law (Box 72a, 289)
    - Education for Professional Responsibility (Box 72a, 289)
    - (Preface) Preparing College Men and Women for Politics (Box 72a, 289)
    - Addresses on Professional Responsibility (Box 72a, 289)
    - John Marshall Bicentennial, 1955 (Box 72a, 289)
    - Cases on Administrative Law (Box 289)
    - Cases on Modern Procedure and Judicial Administration (Box 289)
    - Books initiated by ATV as Chairman of National Conference of Judicial Councils (Box 290)
      [Box 290 Missing as of January 1999.]
      - Orfield: Criminal Procedure from Arrest to Appeal (Box 290)
      - Warren: Traffic Courts (Box 72a)
      - Pound: Appellate Procedure in Civil Cases (Box 72a)
    - Committees on which ATV served (Box 290)
      - Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure (Box 290)
      - Federal Administrative Procedure Act and the Administrative Agencies (Box 290)
    - ATV foreword to MB. Virtue: Basic Structure of Children's Services (Box 290)
    - Annual Survey of American Law initiated by ATV as Dean of NYU, 1942-1952 (Box 72a, 291)
      [Box 291 Missing as of January 1999.]
    - Copies of Thomas H. Reed: Twenty Years of Government in Essex County, New Jersey (Box 72a)
    - Report on Prelegal Education (Box 293)
      - Pamphlets, articles, materials used in writing report (Box 293)
      - Rough drafts and final draft (Box 293)
      - Correspondence, 1941-1949 (Box 293)
      - Replies from colleges (Box 294)
      - Law school letter (Box 294)
      - Replies to Questionnaires (Box 294)
      - Summary of Questionnaire replies (Box 294)
      - Survey of prelegal education (Box 294)
      - Replies to Nov. 1949 questionnaire (Box 295)
      - Drafts of 1950 report (Box 295)
      - Final draft of report (Box 295)
    - Studying Law (Box 296)
      - Correspondence, 1946-1954 (Box 296)
      - Replies from deans of law schools, alphabetically by schools, 1946 (Box 296)
      - Replies from college presidents, alphabetically by colleges, 1946 (Box 296)
      - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 296)
      - Materials not used in book (Box 296)
      - Mailing lists (Box 296)
      - Clippings, reviews, ads (Box 296)
      - Second edition (Box 296)
    - Minimum Standards of Judicial Administration (Box 297)
      - Correspondence, by states, 1948-1951 (Box 297)
      - Appellate Practice (Box 298)
      - Part I. Rule Making (4 folders) (Box 298)
      - Rule-Making (2 folders) (Box 299)
      - Part II. Managing Business of Courts (Box 299)
      - Part III. Pretrial (2 folders) (Box 299)
      - Part IV. Jury Service (2 folders) (Box 300)
      - Part V. Trial Practice (Box 300)
      - Part V. Trial Practice (Box 301)
      - Part VI. Appellate Practice (Box 301)
      - Part VII. Evidence (2 folders) (Box 301)
      - Part VIII. State Administrative Procedures (Box 301)
      - Part IX. Selection and Tenure of Judges (Box 301)
      - Selection and Tenure of Judges (Box 302)
      - File copies of final draft (Box 302)
      - General correspondence (Box 303)
      - Comments on, acknowledgments of (Box 303)
      - Sample questionnaire form letters (Box 303)
      - Parts I-V (Box 303)
      - Part VI (Box 303)
    - Procedure Casebook (Box 304)
      - Correspondence, 1951-1954 (Box 304)
      - Correspondence with Edith S. Levin (research assistant) (Box 304)
      - Questionnaire re teaching of procedure, 1951 (Box 305)
      - Replies to letter re disciplinary action, 1951 (Box 305)
      - Questionnaire re Judge's powers (Box 305)
      - Summary of questionnaires (Box 305)
      - Practice and procedure notes (Box 305)
      - Book reviews (Box 306)
      - Shipping notices (Box 306)
      - Memoranda, suggestions for 2nd edition (Box 306)
    - Folders of engagements [See also Container No. 268], 1956-1957 (Box 307)
    - Lectures and Addresses, 1947-1957 (Box 308)
      - Cook Lectures, preliminary draft, 1949 (Box 308)
      - Cook Lectures, book reviews, acknowledgments (Box 308)
      - Lectures and Addresses, 1947-1957 (Box 308)
      - Pound Lectures, drafts, April 16-18, 1952 (Box 308)
      - Pound Lecture, manuscript and supporting essays (Box 308)
      - Julius Rosenthal Lecture, Northwestern University School of Law, Jan. 13, 1953 (Box 309)
      - Charles E. Hughes Lecture, New York, Feb. 16, 1954 (Box 309)
      - County Lawyers Association (Box 309)
      - Tyrrell William Lectures, April 24, 1956 (Box 309)
      - John Cotton Dana Centennial Address, Oct. 17, 1956 (Box 309)
    - Washington Square Publishing Company (Box 310)
      - Correspondence (A-T) (Box 310)
      - Correspondence (T-Z) (Box 311)
      - Minimum Standard of Judicial Administration (Box 311)
      - Orders filled and paid, 1950 (Box 311)
      - Binding, 1950-1954 (Box 311)
      - Individual Paid Orders, 1946-1950 (Box 312)
    - Three card index files of friends to whom ATV publications were sent (Box 313)
    - Acknowledgments of receipt of ATV publications (11 folders) (Box 314)
- Writings - Unfinished
  - Research Notes Toward a Biography of Lord Mansfield
    - Index file to Lord Mansfield materials (Box 315)
    - Correspondence, 1935-1957 (Box 316)
    - Information on Lord Mansfield: articles, reprints, notes, etc. (Box 317)
    - Information on Lord Mansfield: articles, reprints, notes and loose materials (Box 318)
    - Photostatic materials (Box 319-319a)
    - Microfilm (8 rolls) (Box 320)
      Contents described below according to labels on microfilm.
      - Roll A: Law cases; see index attached.
        No index attached.
      - Roll B: Law cases; see index attached.
      - Roll C: This reel contains maritime cases during the war with Spain and France.
      - Roll #7: Court cases: starts 1. Andrew Scott, Deacon etc., Bakers of Glasgow; 2. Sir John Dindey; 3. Peter Mackattie; 4. John Chalie; 5. Richard Tucker; 6. Lord Pitsligo; 7. Noah Webb; 8. James Duke of Athol; 9. Case of John; 10. Richard Earl of Burlington. Ends with unreadable script.
      - Roll #8: The Case of Alexander Late Lord Pitsligo; treason
      - Roll #9: This roll appears to be a journal containing record of case on maritime law? Much of it is overexposed and difficult reading.
      - Roll #10: Material on this roll relates in part to the Lord Ravenworths case which appeared on an earlier roll of file which is now in your possession.
      - Unnumbered roll: This roll is overexposed and unreadable.
    - Bibliography; Card index file (Box 321)
    - Card Index File (Box 322)
      - Biographical Material (Box 322)
      - William Murray cases (Box 323)
      - Legal Work of Murray (Box 324)
      - Political activities of Mansfield by subject (Box 325)
      - Political chronology of Murray's career (Box 326)
      - Decisions of Lord Mansfield, A-O (Box 327)
      - Decisions of Lord Mansfie1d, P-Z (Box 328)
    - Loose index cards on Mansfield (Box 329)
    - Loose index cards on Mansfield (Box 330)
    - Card Index File, unlabeled (Box 331)
  - Notes and Rough Drafts Toward "A History of the Development of the Administration of Justice in the United States"
    - Correspondence (5 folders), 1953-1957 (Box 332)
    - Drafts. Introduction and Part I (4 folders) (Box 333)
    - Drafts. Chapter II, Chapter III (2 folders) (Box 334)
    - Drafts. Chapters III, IV, VII, and V (Box 335)
    - Notes, Chapter VI, Chapter II (Box 336)
    - Notes, materials and correspondence (5 folders) (Box 337)
    - Notes and materials (2 folders) (Box 338)
    - Notes and materials (6 folders) (Box 339)
    - Notes and materials (4 folders) (Box 340)
    - Notes and materials (4 folders) (Box 341)
    - Notes and materials (5 folders) (Box 342)
    - Notes and materials (3 folders) (Box 343)
    - Notes and materials (6 folders) (Box 344)
    - Notes and materials (5 folders) (Box 345)
    - Notes and materials (5 folders) (Box 346)
    - Card Index File. Notes (Box 347)
- Miscellaneous: Photographs, Travel, Personal Interests
  - Photographs--personal, lawyers, judges, bar association meetings (Box 348)
  - Photographs--personal, lawyers, judges, bar association meetings (Box 348a)
  - Photographs--personal, lawyers, judges, bar association meetings (Box 349)
  - Photographs--personal, lawyers, judges, bar association meetings (Box 349a)
  - Photographs--personal, lawyers, judges, bar association meetings (Box 350)
  - Photographs--personal, lawyers, judges, bar association meetings (Box 350a)
  - Photographs--personal, lawyers, judges, bar association meetings (Box 351)
  - Photographs--personal, lawyers, judges, bar association meetings (Box 352)
  - Photographs--personal, lawyers, judges, bar association meetings (Box 378)
  - Photographs--personal, lawyers, judges, bar association meetings (Box 379)
  - Miscellaneous photographs (Box 353)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 354)
  - 18th and 19th century books concerning New Jersey courts and law (Box 355)
    - Law Dictionary and Glossary..., 1717 (Box 355)
    - An Institute of the Laws of England, 1778 (Box 355)
    - An Act to Regulate and Fix the Terms for Holding the Court of Appeals, 1784 (Box 355)
    - Minutes of the Court of Appeals, 1844 (Box 355)
    - Rules of the Supreme Court, 1885 (Box 355)
    - Ledger of the Minutes of the New Jersey Court of Appeals, 1825 (Box 355)
    - Acts of the General Assembly of the Province of New Jersey, 1864 (Box 355)
    - Rules of the Supreme Court of the State of New Jersey, 1864 (Box 355)
    - Laws of the State of New Jersey, 1800 (Box 380)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 356)
  - Books on New Jersey courts and law (Box 357)
  - National Civil Service Reform League (Box 358)
  - National Committee for Feeding Starving Children (2 folders) (Box 358)
  - Civil Liberties, pamphlets (Box 358)
  - National Probation Association (Box 358)
  - National Probation Association (2 folders) (Box 359)
  - C.P.A. Society of New Jersey (Box 359)
  - American Counsel Association (Box 359)
  - Trip to Italy, April 15, 1953, 1954 (Box 360)
  - Roman Law (Box 360)
  - North Harpswell, Maine, search notes (Box 360)
  - Newspaper clipping service (Box 360)
  - Inter-County Republican Committee (Box 361)
  - Politics, 1936 (Box 361)
  - Dictaphone recording discs (with recordings) (Box 362)
  - Survey of the Legal Profession (2 folders) (Box 363)
  - Education for Government (3 folders) (Box 364)
  - National Rededication (Box 365)
  - American University Board of Trustees, 1941-1945 (Box 365)
  - Citizen's National Committee (Box 365)
  - Legal Aid pamphlets (Box 365)
  - Legal Aid (Box 366)
  - Integration of Bar pamphlets (2 folders) (Box 366)
  - Congressional Investigating Committees, 1942-1945 (Box 367)
  - National Foundation for Education in American Citizenship (Box 368)
  - Judge John J. Parker. Drive to put on U.S. Supreme Court, correspondence, 1942 (Box 369)
  - Court Packing controversy, correspondence, 1937 (Box 369)
  - U.S. Government Foreign Policy; a written transcript (Box 369)
  - Committee on Public Administration, Social Science Rescue Council (Box 369)
  - Suburban Essex Republican Union (Box 370)
  - Survey of Legal Profession (Box 370)
  - Biography of James E. Stiles (Box 371)
  - ATV biographical materials (Box 371)
  - ATV trip to Spain, 1956 (Box 371)
  - Article on ATV by Jerome Spingarn (Box 371)
  - Clippings on Hague and Norman Thomas (Box 371)
  - Miscellaneous File Information (Box 371)
  - ATV Short Hills, New Jersey residence (Box 371)
  - Proposed office building (Box 371)
  - Connecticut farm, proposed purchase (Box 371)
  - Delt Development program (Box 371)
  - Miscellaneous unlabeled files (Box 372)
  - Miscellaneous unlabeled files (Box 373)
  - Miscellaneous materials (Box 374-377)